Today is a great day of Mahalakshmi Puja.
Dzisiaj jest wielki dzień pujy do Mahalakshmi.
Mahalakshmi is an incarnation
Mahalakshmi jest inkarnacją
of the Lakshmi, the power of Vishnu.
Lakshmi, mocy Vishnu.
She only incar­nated.
Tylko ona inkarnowała.
This Mahalakshmi principle
Ta zasada Mahalakshmi
is born out of the Lakshmi,
jest zrodzona z Lakshmi,
who is the power of Sri Vishnu.
która jest mocą Shri Vishnu.
When in a human being
Kiedy w istocie ludzkiej
the desire to rise higher comes in,
pojawia się pragnienie wzniesienia się wyżej,
the Lakshmi principle becomes the Mahalakshmi principle.
zasada Lakshmi staje się zasadą Mahalakshmi.
Like in the West we can say,
Tak jak na Zachodzie,
people have affluence of Lakshmi,
gdy ludzie posiadają już dobrobyt Lakshmi,
so they wanted to rise above that principle
chcieli wznieść się ponad tę zasadę
and become Mahalakshmi.
i stać się Mahalakshmi.
In the awareness it acts on the matter like aesthetics;
W świadomości działa to jako estetyka,
people worry more about aesthetics
ludzie troszczą się bardziej o estetykę
than about possessions.
niż o posiadanie.
And when they start growing
A kiedy zaczynają rosnąć
higher and higher in their awareness of seeking,
wyżej i wyżej w swojej świadomości poszukiwania,
then they find that
wtedy odkrywają,
the attention should be such,
że uwaga powinna być taka,
that they should pay more im­portance
aby przywiązywać większe znaczenie
to the aesthetics of things
do estetyki rzeczy,
than to the gross values.
niż do przyziemnych wartości.
Now when this desire becomes
Zatem, gdy to pragnienie staje się
evident in human beings,
w ludzkich istotach ewidentne,
then only Lakshmi incarnates as Mahalakshmi.
tylko wtedy Lakshmi inkarnuje jako Mahalakshmi.
So She incarnated as Mahalakshmi
Tak więc Ona inkarnowała jako Mahalakshmi
when Rama came on this earth, first time.
pierwszy raz, gdy Rama przybył na Ziemię.
And also She incarnated as Radha
Inkarnowała także jako Radha,
when Shri Krishna came on this earth.
kiedy Shri Krishna przyszedł na tę Ziemię.
And when She came as Mary,
A kiedy przybyła jako Maryja,
it was Mahalakshmi
to była Mahalakshmi,
who bore the child that is Lord Jesus Christ.
która urodziła dziecko będące Jezusem Chrystusem.
So the child She bore
Więc to dziecko, które urodziła,
was the great personality, of Mahavishnu.
było wielką osobowością, Mahavishnu.
This Mahavishnu-tattwa is also represented,
Ta zasada Mahavishnu jest również reprezentowana,
or we can say has an aspect,
lub możemy powiedzieć, ma aspekt
of others, which in­carnated on this earth
innych, którzy inkarnowali na tej Ziemi
as two children of Sita.
jako dwoje dzieci Sity [Kush i Luv].
They incarnated as
Oni inkarnowali jako
Mahavira and Buddha, as Hassan and Hussein.
Mahavira i Buddha, jako Hassan i Hussein.
Also at the time of the prophets
Również w czasach proroków
Mahalakshmi incarnates as
Mahalakshmi inkarnuje jako
a pure relationship with them.
czysta relacja [pokrewieństwo] z nimi.
Like Raja Janaka’s daughter was Janaki,
Jako Janaki, córka Króla Janaka,
means Sita;
czyli Sita;
then She came on this earth
następnie Ona przyszła na tę Ziemię
as the daughter of Mohammed Sahib;
jako córka Mahometa;
and then She came on this earth as Nanaki,
a potem przyszła na tę Ziemię jako Nanaki,
the sister of Nanaka.
siostra Nanaka.
So She resides as a pure relationship
Rezyduje więc Ona jako czysty związek
of these gurus.
tych guru.
Thus the Mahalakshmi’s greatness is that,
W ten sposób, wspaniałością Mahalakshmi jest to,
through Her power only the Sushumna
że tylko poprzez Jej moc, Sushumna
is cover­ed by Kundalini.
jest wypełniona przez Kundalini.
She is the power of our evol­ution.
Ona jest mocą naszej ewolucji.
And by Her power only
I tylko dzięki Jej mocy,
we have risen to be human beings
wzrośliśmy, aby stać się istotami ludzkimi
and by Her son’s power
a przez siłę Jej syna
we are going to become higher people.
staniemy się wyższymi ludźmi.
Thus the impor­tance of Mahalakshmi is very great
Zatem znaczenie Mahalakshmi jest bardzo wielkie
for all the Sahaja Yogis.
dla wszystkich Sahaja yoginów.
Because She guides our Vishnu tattwa
Ponieważ Ona kieruje naszą zasadą Vishnu
to its culmination, to its completion,
do jej kulminacji, do jej ukończenia,
which is the principle of our evolution.
co jest zasadą naszej ewolucji.
Thus She is a giver of Dharma,
W ten sposób Ona jest dawczynią Dharmy,
She gives us the Dharma and
daje nam Dharmę
She is the giver of the truth.
i daje nam prawdę.
She is the one who relates us to our brain,
Ona łączy nas z naszym mózgiem.
the whole brain’s system is Mahalakshmi’s system.
Cały system mózgu jest systemem Mahalakshmi.
So it is She who exposes
Więc to Ona odsłania dla nas
the whole of the knowledge as truth to us,
całą wiedzę jako prawdę,
on our central nervous system.
na naszym centralnym systemie nerwowym.
But at the state of Virata,
Ale w stanie Viraty,
when Vishnu becomes the Virata,
kiedy Vishnu staje się Viratą,
the great primordial being,
wielkim pierwotnym bytem,
then She is called as Viratangana, as his power.
Ona nazywana jest Viratanganą, jako jego moc.
So these are the incarnations of Mahala­kshmi
Zatem to są inkarnacje Mahalakshmi,
about which I have told.
o których wam mówiłam.
There’s so much can be said about this Mahalakshmi­tattwa;
Tak wiele można powiedzieć o tej zasadzie Mahalakshmi;
you are all blessed so much by that.
jesteście wszyscy przez to tak błogosławieni.
And so today we remember
Więc dzisiaj pamiętamy
Her great in­carnation as Maria,
Jej wielką inkarnację jako Maryję,
who was very great because
która była tak wspaniała, ponieważ
She had to bear terrible pain in Her heart
Ona musiała znieść straszliwy ból w sercu,
with all Her powers that She had,
ze wszystkich sił jakie posiadała.
She was a tremendously powerful Lady.
Ona była niesłychanie potężną kobietą.
But despite that, She bore all the tortures
Ale pomimo tego, zniosła wszystkie tortury
of Christ upon Her heart.
Chrystusa w swoim sercu.
And it was Her order and Her desire
I to było Jej rozkazem i pragnieniem,
that Christ had to crucify Himself
że Chrystus musiał ukrzyżować siebie,
so that people could be resurrected.
żeby ludzie mogli zostać wskrzeszeni.
And sometimes Indians ask Me
I czasami Hindusi pytają Mnie,
what did She do to be a Mahalakshmi, what did She achieve?
co Ona zrobiła, aby być Mahalakshmi, co Ona osiągnęła?
I said: “With all Her powers to bear it.
Powiedziałam: "Mimo wszystkich swoich mocy, aby to wytrzymać,
To play the drama it must be too much.”
aby odegrać ten dramat - to musiało być zbyt wiele".
So She is the redeemer and She connects you to God.
Zatem Ona jest zbawicielem i łączy was z Bogiem.
In the sense She is the bridge.
W tym sensie, że jest mostem.
And the Kundalini rises over the bridge.
A Kundalini wznosi się po moście.
And Kundalini is the Mahakali.
I Kundalini jest Mahakali.
Now we have a temple in India
Teraz mamy świątynię
which you have visited of Mahalakshmi in Kolhapur;
Mahalakshmi w Kolhapur, w Indiach, którą zwiedziliście
and there, when they sing,
i w niej kiedy się śpiewa,
when they worship Mahalakshmi
kiedy czci się Mahalakshmi,
at that time they say “udho, udho,Ambe”.
mówi się przez cały czas: "Udho, udho Ambe".
That time they say: “O Ambe, the Kundalini, you rise”.
Mówi się w tym czasie: "O Ambe, o Kundalini, wznieś się!"
But Kundalini is the potential of all the three powers:
Ale Kundalini jest potencjałem wszystkich trzech mocy:
Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati,
Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati,
because it is the primordial desire.
ponieważ jest to pierwotne pragnienie.
Because She is the Holy Ghost, you see,
Ponieważ Ona jest Świętym Duchem, widzicie,
so She contains all these three powers in it.
więc Ona zawiera w sobie wszystkie te trzy moce.
Like Adi Shakti has all the three powers
Tak jak Adi Shakti posiada wszystkie te trzy moce
of Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati.
Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati.
So now today is a great day for us
Dlatego dzisiejszy dzień jest dla nas wspaniały,
because Mahalakshmi has helped us so much,
ponieważ Mahalakshmi tak bardzo nam pomogła,
Her blessings are much.
Jej błogosławieństw jest wiele.
She looks after all our well-­being,
Ona troszczy się o całą naszą  pomyślność,
She is the one who looks after
Ona troszczy się
all our problems of redemption,
o wszystkie problemy naszego zbawienia,
She is the one who gives us all the possible
Ona jest Tą, która daje nam wszelką możliwą
help in our Chakras and correction of them.
pomoc w naszych czakrach oraz ich korektę.
And She is the one who gives us
Ona też obdarza nas
all that is material or physical well­ being
materialnym i fizycznym dobrobytem
so we have to be very very thankful to Her today.
tak więc dzisiaj musimy być Jej bardzo wdzięczni.
You have to be grateful.
Musicie być wdzięczni.
And also today is Gregoire’s birthday.
Dzisiaj również są urodziny Gregoire'a.
So I would like to congratulate him
Tak więc chciałabym mu pogratulować,
for making Me come to Munich
za to, że sprowadził Mnie do Monachium,
because we had such a tremendous programme
ponieważ mieliśmy tak wspaniały program.
May God bless you all.
Niech Bóg błogosławi was wszystkich.